newbalance.co.uk 2018-12-04

# Privacy Policy

## PRIVACY AND COOKIE POLICY

### LAST UPDATED: May 25, 2018

### [**I. PRIVACY POLICY**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_policy)

### [**II. COOKIE POLICY**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#cookie_policy)

### **I. PRIVACY POLICY**

Thank you for placing your trust in New Balance. We are committed to protecting your privacy and take our responsibilities regarding the safety and security of customer’s personal information very seriously. This Privacy Policy describes what personal information we collect about you, how and why we collect and use it, who has access to it and what your privacy rights are. Please review it carefully.

This Privacy Policy is provided in a layered format so you can click through to the specific sections set out below:

### [**1\. WHEN DOES THIS PRIVACY POLICY APPLY TO ME?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_1)

### [**2\. WHO IS RESPONSIBLE FOR MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_2)

### [**3\. WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION DOES NEW BALANCE COLLECT ABOUT ME AND HOW?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_3)

### [**4\. FOR WHAT PURPOSES DOES NEW BALANCE USE MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_4)

### [**5\. WHAT IS THE LEGAL BASIS FOR NEW BALANCE’S USE OF MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_5)

### [**6\. WITH WHOM DOES NEW BALANCE SHARE MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_6)

### [**7\. HOW IS MY PERSONAL INFORMATION KEPT SECURE?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_7)

### [**8\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_8)

### [**9\. WHAT IS THE NEW BALANCE CHILDREN'S PRIVACY POLICY?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_9)

### [**10\. HOW DO LINKS FROM NEW BALANCE TO OTHER SITES OR APPS AFFECT ME?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_10)

### [**11\. FOR HOW LONG DOES NEW BALANCE KEEP MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_11)

### [**12\. WHAT ARE MY PRIVACY RIGHTS?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_12)

### [**13\. HOW CAN I OPT-OUT/UNSUBSCRIBE FROM NEW BALANCE MARKETING EMAILS?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_13)

### [**14\. HOW CAN I ACCESS, UPDATE OR DELETE "MY ACCOUNT" INFORMATION?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_14)

### [**15\. HOW CAN I CONTACT NEW BALANCE IF I HAVE QUESTIONS OR COMPLAINTS ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_15)

### [**16\. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND YOUR DUTY TO INFORM US OF CHANGES**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_16)

**Please note that you have the right to object to us processing your personal information for our legitimate business purposes or for direct marketing purposes (including any related profiling we do to help ensure that our marketing is relevant to our customers’ interests). For more information about your right to object and how you can exercise it, please see section 12. WHAT ARE MY PRIVACY RIGHTS?**

###  **1\. WHEN DOES THIS PRIVACY POLICY APPLY TO ME?**

This Privacy Policy applies to all personal information collected by New Balance Athletic Shoes (U.K.) Limited and its affiliates, either in New Balance retail stores or through the operation of the following services:

    * • www.newbalance.co.uk, and any other website operated by or on behalf of New Balance Athletics Shoes (U.K.) Limited, including but not limited to the following (the " **Website** "):
    * www.newbalance.de
    * www.newbalance.es
    * www.newbalance.pt
    * www.newbalance.ie
    * www.newbalance.se
    * www.newbalance.lv
    * si.newbalance.eu
    * www.newbalance.fr
    * www.newbalance.it
    * www.newbalance.be
    * dk.newbalance.eu
    * fi.newbalance.eu
    * www.newbalance.lu
    * ee.newbalance.eu
    * lt.newbalance.eu
    * nl.newbalance.eu
    * at.newbalance.eu
    * www.newbalance.com.gr
    * www.newbalance.co.hu
    * cz.newbalance.eu
    * www.nbblackoutsquad.com;

    * • all services made available by New Balance through the Website; and

    * • the Stride I.D. Experience made available by New Balance in selected stores.

For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, the services listed above (including the operation of New Balance retail stores) are referred to collectively as, the " **Service** ”.

This Privacy Policy applies whether you are a " **Visitor** " (which means that you simply browse the Service) or you are a " **Member** " (which means that you have registered for “My Account” with New Balance, have purchased any products on our Website or used any component of the Service).

###  **2\. WHO IS RESPONSIBLE FOR MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

New Balance Athletic Shoes (U.K.) Limited (a company registered in England and Wales with company number 01616165 and registered address at Appleton House, 430 Birchwood Boulevard, Birchwood, Warrington, Cheshire, WA3 7WD, UK) and New Balance Athletics, Inc. (a company registered in Massachusetts, USA and registered address at 100 Guest Street, Boston, MA 02135 USA) are the joint “data controllers” of the personal information that is collected about you when you use the Service (referred to in this Privacy Policy as “ **New Balance** ”, " **we** ", " **us** ", or " **our** "). This means that we control the ways your personal information are collected in connection with the Service and determine how and why such personal information is used for the purposes of applicable data protection law.

###  **3\. WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION DOES NEW BALANCE COLLECT ABOUT ME AND HOW?**

Personal information (or personal data) is any information which identifies you personally whether directly (for example, your name) or indirectly (for example, information about your use of the Service).

**_Information you give to us_**

We collect the following personal information from you:

      * **• Basic identity and contact information:** We collect your name, title, postal/delivery address, email address and telephone number if you purchase any products on our Website. We may also collect some or all of this information if you:

      * o register for “My Account” on our Website;

      * o complete the “About Me” questionnaire to tell us about your shopping preferences, in which we may also collect your gender, shoe size, shoe width, clothing size, hobbies, shopping preferences, information about your weekly workouts and whether you have kids and their genders;

      * o sign up to receive our marketing communications;

      * o enter any of our competitions, contests, promotions, surveys or questionnaires, in which we may also collect your social media handle(s);

      * o contact or correspond with us about the Service (or any component of it); and/or

      * o participate in a New Balance run club.

      * **• Payment information:** We collect your payment card details and billing address if you purchase any products on our Website. We won’t retain your payment card details for longer than is necessary in order to fulfil your order. However, if you register for “My Account", you can choose to store your payment card details in your account so that you don’t have to re-enter your full payment card details the next time you make a purchase. Please see section [**7\. HOW IS MY PERSONAL INFORMATION KEPT SECURE?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_7) to find out more about how we safeguard your payment card details;

      * **• Transaction information:** We keep a record of your order history, including the products purchased and the date, time and value of each transaction, and your billing and shipping address;

      * **• Account login:** If you register for “My Account”, we keep a record of your account login username and email address in case you need reminding of these in the future;

      * **• Correspondence and feedback:** We collect any additional personal information that you may provide to us from time to time when you visit a New Balance retail store, if you complete a survey or questionnaire or contact us by email, letter, telephone or through our Website. If you contact us by telephone, we may also record the call for training and service improvement purposes, and make notes in relation to your call; and

      * **• Marketing and communications preferences:** We collect information regarding your preferences in receiving marketing from us and your communications preferences.

**_Information you give to us if you participate in the Stride I.D. Experience_**

The New Balance Stride I.D. Experience features scan technology provided by our technology provider Volumental that uses infrared imaging to create a three-dimensional (3D) image of your feet and collects key measurements about you and your feet, including your gender, foot length, foot width, arch height, strike, flexibility and foot size. The scan technology also creates a shoe profile including foot size and foot width in order to generate a 3D mesh image of your feet.

The scan technology can also be combined with gait analysis technology, which involves conducting a video analysis of your feet as you run to measure your gait.

We also collect information about the shoe model you try on and if you make a purchase. 

Together, this information is used to help us provide a better fit recommendation matched to your needs and find the perfect shoes to optimise the performance of athletes.

Where you elect to receive a copy of your 3D foot scan (and where applicable a snapshot image from your gait analysis video) we also collect your name, email address, telephone number and age range and retain this information with your Stride I.D. and gait measurement metrics. If you elect not to receive a copy of your 3D foot scan image or snapshot image from your gait analysis video, we will delete your gait analysis video and will retain only the resulting measurement data from which we cannot identify you. We retain this information in order to better understand and improve how our products fit.

We share the measurement data (but never your contact information) with Volumental, who use this information to improve their scanning technology. Volumental also retains the raw infrared images from your scan and the resulting 3D mesh image for the same purpose of improving their foot scanning technology to offer customers best fit solutions. We never share any contact information (such as your name or email address) with Volumental. If, after your scan, you object to the processing as described in this section, we will delete your scan and any measurement data and instruct Volumental to do the same.

**_Information we collect from other sources_**

We also obtain information about you from other sources:

        * • **CCTV** : If you visit a New Balance retail store, we may collect your image as a result of our use of CCTV.

        * • **Cookies and similar technologies** : When you visit our Website we use cookies and similar technologies, such as web beacons and pixel tags, to automatically collect information about:

        * • your browsing activity and use of the Service; and

        * • the device you have used to access our Website (including the make, model and operating system, internet protocol (IP) address (from which we may derive your geographic location), browser type and mobile device identifiers).

We also engage third parties who place cookies on our Website to collect the same or similar information and share the information with New Balance. Please see our [**COOKIE POLICY**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#cookie_policy) for further details.

        * • **Social Media** : If you mention New Balance or New Balance-related information in a posting on any social media platform, such as Facebook, Instagram or YouTube, we may collect publicly-available information about your post, including your name, social media handle, your location, the date and time of your post, the content of your post and any images and/or videos included with your post. We will only collect data that the social media provider has expressly permitted us to receive as a result of your privacy settings on those social media platforms. We do not have any control over the privacy practices of the social media platforms; please see their privacy statements for details of how they use your personal information, whom they share it with and how to manage your privacy settings on those platforms.

        * • **Fit Finder** : If while on the Website you use our “Fit Finder” feature, we will collect your height, weight, body shape, clothing size, sizing preferences and age in order to recommend a size that fits you based on sizes purchased by other people similar to you. You are not identifiable from the information you submit and we do not link any information you provide through this feature with you or your account.

        * • Except for information we collect through the operation of CCTV in New Balance retail stores, which we keep separate at all times, we may combine the personal information we collect from you and from the other sources listed above. We do this to help us ensure that the information we hold about you is kept up to date and to form a clearer picture about our customer base so that we can understand the kinds of offers in which you might be interested and improve the Service in the future.

### **4\. FOR WHAT PURPOSES DOES NEW BALANCE USE MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

We use the personal information that you submit to us or that we collect about you through your use of the Service for the following purposes: 

**_To process your orders and returns_**

We need to use your personal information to process any orders and returns you make in accordance with our Terms and Conditions. This activity includes contacting you to confirm when you have successfully placed an order, managing payments, fees and charges, and collecting and recovering any money owed to us. It requires us to process your identity and contact information, payment information and transaction information.

**_To register you for, and manage, "My Account”_**

If you wish to create an account using the "My Account" service, we need to process your identity and contact information. You will also be asked to provide account login details. Once the account has been created, we use this information to identify you as a new or returning customer and manage your account going forwards. This includes keeping a record of your account login details (your username and email address) in case you need reminding of these in the future.

**_To provide you with the services available through our Website_**

In order to provide certain services through our Website, we need to process your personal information. For example, New Balance uses your personal information for the following purposes with respect to providing you with services available through our Website:

          * • **“Find a Store” feature** : by inputting your post code or city, we can help you to locate a New Balance retail store;
          * • **Inventory** : We use your location information to provide you recommendations of stores nearby that have product inventory available;
          * • **“Help” or “Live Chat”** : New Balance customer service representatives may communicate with you in real time to assist you with any questions you have while you are on the Website;
          * • **Idea Submission** : to submit an invention and idea for New Balance’s evaluation, we request you to fill out a submission form with your name, company, address, phone and email so we may contact you if needed regarding your submission;
          * • **Job Application** : if you apply for a job through our Website, you will be taken to our third party provider Workday’s site and asked to provide an email address to create a Workday account;
          * • **“Fit Finder” feature** : we collect sizing and other personal information to assist us with recommending a size for a particular product; and/or
          * • **Newsletter** : to sign up to our newsletter, we will collect your email address in order to send you the newsletters.

**_To manage your relationship with us_**

We use your identity and contact information to manage our relationship with you in connection with the Service, including notifying you of changes to the terms of any contracts between us or to any related information (such as changes to this Privacy Policy).

**_To operate the Stride I.D. Experience_**

If you participate in the Stride I.D. Experience and have provided your consent to do so, we use the information collected from you to:

            * • send you a copy of or provide access through your New Balance Account to your 3D foot scan and (where applicable) a snapshot image from the video of you running for your gait analysis; 
            * • provide analysis and advice as to which products are best suited to your needs;
            * • call you to get your feedback on your Stride I.D. Experience and find out how our products are performing;
            * • contact you by telephone or email about other New Balance products, services and offers where you have consented to receiving these marketing communications from us; and
            * • carry out analysis on the information received (on an aggregated, non-identifiable basis) to help improve the Stride I.D. Experience.

For more information about the Stride I.D. Experience, see section [**3\. WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION DOES NEW BALANCE COLLECT ABOUT ME AND HOW.**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_3)

**_To keep New Balance retail stores secure_**

We operate CCTV at our retail stores where necessary to monitor security and safeguard the safety of visitors and staff. There are prominent signs in the areas where CCTV is operated. Your image may be collected if you visit one of our stores. Any CCTV footage is automatically deled after three months.

Please note that access to CCTV footage is restricted to authorised New Balance staff only. It is not shared with any third party, except law enforcement agencies in limited circumstances where we are required to make such disclosure by law for the prevention and detection of crime.

**_To deliver relevant marketing to you (which involves automated decision-making and profiling in order to personalise and improve your customer experience)_**

**Our marketing communications**

If you have provided your consent to do so, we will use your identity, contact information and preferences to send you marketing communications by email about our products and services, including our newsletters and details of special offers and promotions which we think might be of interest to you.

You can unsubscribe or opt-out of our marketing communications at any time. See section [**13\. HOW CAN I OPT-OUT/UNSUBSCRIBE FROM NEW BALANCE MARKETING EMAILS?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_13) for details of how to do this. 

**Our use of automated decision-making and profiling**

We want to ensure that the marketing communications we send to you are relevant to your interests. Consequently, we use cookies and other similar technologies (if you have accepted them) to track and analyse your use of our Website, the services available through them and your interaction with any marketing communications that we send to you to help us build a profile of your preferences. For example, we collect information on how you browse our Website, including the web pages or products you have viewed or put in your shopping basket, in order to help us understand what you like.

What this means for you is that, if you have agreed to receiving marketing communications from us, you are more likely to receive messages, special offers and promotions that we think you might like and are tailored to your preferences, based on your previous activity. It also means that we do not send the same marketing communications to all of our customers, so you may not be made the same offers as another customer.

In addition, we may use the information we collect about your preferences in order to display content and offers on our Website and other websites and apps that are more relevant to you and your interests.

This may include delivering targeted advertising on our Website or other websites and apps that you access, or limiting the number of times you see a particular advertisement.

Please see our [**COOKIE POLICY**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#cookie_policy) to find out more about our use of cookies and how you can manage your cookie preferences.

If you don’t agree with an automated decision that our technology has made in relation to you or you wish to object to us using profiling to send you tailored marketing communications and deliver targeted advertising, you can let us know (see section [**15\. HOW CAN I CONTACT NEW BALANCE IF I HAVE QUESTIONS OR COMPLAINTS ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_15)). If you do object, we won't be able to continue to send you tailored marketing communications, which means the offers you receive from us may not be as relevant to you.

Please note that the legal basis for us tailoring our marketing communications to your preferences is that it is in our legitimate interests to do so, having taken into account whether your interests and fundamental rights and freedoms are overridden by this type of processing. See section [**5\. WHAT IS NEW BALANCE’S LEGAL BASIS FOR ITS USE OF MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_5) for more information about what our legitimate interests are.

**_To communicate with you on social media_**

If you include New Balance or New Balance-related information in a social media posting, we may use the publicly-available information that you post to communicate with you regarding the post. We may also aggregate the data with data from other social media posts regarding New Balance (from which you cannot be identified) to better understand and more effectively manage New Balance’s social media presence and marketing campaigns.

**_To run competitions and contests_**

If you choose to enter a competition, contest or survey that we run, including those that we run on third party sites, we need to use your identity and contact information and any other personal information that you provide at the time of entry so that we can manage the competition or contest (as applicable).

**_To administer and protect our business and Website_**

We process your personal information in the course of administering our business and Website. This includes troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data.

**_To use data analytics to improve our Website marketing and the services available through our Website_**

We rely on the use of personal information to build a clearer picture of our customers both as a group and as individuals. We do this by using cookies and similar technologies to capture and analyse your use of our Website, the services available through them and your interaction with any marketing communications that we send to you. We may also aggregate this information on an anonymous basis with information relating to other customers for analytical purposes.

This enables us to serve you better as a customer as the information we gather helps us to improve:

              * • our Website and the information technology systems (including security) that are used to operate them;
              * • our product selection and the services we provide through our Website; and
              * • the effectiveness of our marketing communications to you.

Please see our [**COOKIE POLICY**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#cookie_policy) to find out more about our use of cookies and how you can manage your cookie preferences.

**_To provide and improve Customer Care_**

We use your personal information to be able to provide and improve our Customer Care service. For example, we use the personal information we hold about you to help us address any enquiries or complaints you have made, or deal with any dispute which may arise in the course of us providing the Service to you.

**_To conduct market research_**

We may invite you to be involved in market research, such as customer surveys or questionnaires. If you accept our invitation, we will use your feedback to improve the Service. If you tell us that you don't wanted to be contacted about market research, or you don't accept our invitation, we will respect this choice and it won't affect your ability to access and use the Service.

**_To comply with our legal obligations and to detect, prevent and investigate other actual or suspected violations of law or misuse of our Service_**

In certain circumstances, we use your personal information only to the extent required in order to enable us to comply with our legal obligations, including to detect, prevent and investigate fraud or to facilitate the exercise of your consumer rights. In addition, we may need to use your personal information to detect, prevent and investigate any other actual or suspected violations of law or misuse of our Service.

###  **5\. WHAT IS THE LEGAL BASIS FOR NEW BALANCE’S USE OF MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

Data protection law requires us to only process your personal information if there is a legal basis for us to do so. These are set out in data protection law and we rely on a number of different legal bases for the processing we carry out. These are as follows:

**_Consent_**

In certain circumstances, we process your personal information after obtaining your consent to do so for the purposes of:

                * • sending you marketing communications;

                * • conducting market research; and

                * • operating the Stride I.D. Experience and providing our customers with advice on their best shoe fit in connection with the Stride I.D. Experience.

**_Necessary for the performance of a contract between us_**

It is necessary for us to process your identity and contact information, payment information, transaction information and account login details for the performance of certain contracts between us. This includes, for example, terms and conditions relating to the use of our Website and the services made available through it, the sale of our products and the operation of our competitions and contests. In particular, we rely on this legal ground to process your orders, returns and payments, register you for “My Account”, manage your account and your relationship with us, run competitions and contests and provide and improve Customer Care. 

**_Necessary to comply with our legal obligations_**

In certain circumstances, we use your personal information only to the extent required in order to enable us to comply with our legal obligations, including to detect, prevent and investigate fraud or to facilitate the exercise of your consumer rights. 

**_Necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interests_**

It is sometimes necessary for us to collect and use your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy for the purposes of our legitimate interests as a business, which are to:

                  * • provide our customers with products and services that are as useful and beneficial as possible, including by personalising our contact with customers and telling customers about offers that we think might be of interest to them;

                  * • develop and improve our Website to enhance the customer experience;

                  * • safeguard the security and effective operation of the Service;

                  * • better understand our customer base by engaging with customers and conducting research into, and analysis of, how customers use each of our services and interact with us so that we can improve those services as well as our product selection, marketing activities and communications (all of which could also benefit you);

                  * • train our staff so that we can provide our customers with a better customer service;

                  * • ensure effective operational management and internal administration of our business, including in relation to keeping our records, Website updated, document retention, IT security, compliance with regulatory guidance and exercise or defence of legal claims; and

                  * • provide a safer, more secure environment for visitors and staff at New Balance retail stores, and to protect our property.

Please contact us if you would like further information regarding the balancing tests that we have carried out (see section [**15\. HOW CAN I CONTACT NEW BALANCE IF I HAVE QUESTIONS OR COMPLAINTS ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_15)).

###  **6\. WITH WHOM DOES NEW BALANCE SHARE MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

For the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, we may have to share your personal information with the following third parties:

• **New Balance affiliates** : Our business is headquartered in the U.S. and we operate on a global scale. In order to provide the services you request from us, including participation in the Stride I.D. Experience, our affiliates and participating stores may need to access your personal information. Our affiliates will only use your information for the purposes for which it was originally collected in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Some of our affiliates are located in countries outside of the EEA and where we transfer your information outside of the EEA, we do so under specific contracts approved by the European Commission, which give personal information the same protection it has within the EEA as further described in section [**8\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_8).

• **Third party service providers:** For the purpose of operating our business, we may need to transfer your personal information to our third party service providers who use that information to conduct New Balance business on our instructions and act as “data processors” on our behalf for the purposes of applicable data protection law. Some of our third party service providers are located in countries outside of the EEA and where we transfer your information outside of the EEA, we make sure adequate safeguards are used to protect your personal information, including using specific contracts approved by the European Commission and/or ensuring the service providers located in the United States are part of the EU-US Privacy Shield as further described in section [**8\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_8).

For example, our third party service providers assist us with credit card processing, shipping, data management, email distribution, information analysis, promotions management and other related services for New Balance. We provide our preferred service providers with the personal information they need to perform their services and work with them to ensure your personal information is protected. 

Where you elect to participate in the Stride I.D. Experience, we share certain information with Volumental as described in section [**3\. WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION DOES NEW BALANCE COLLECT ABOUT ME AND HOW**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_3).

• **Third parties providing targeted product recommendations and other communications:** We use third party companies to help serve targeted product recommendations and other communications. To enable these companies to provide you with targeted recommendations and other communications, we may provide these companies with certain personal information about you, such as your name, address and email address, as well as your transaction history. These third parties may also collect information about your browsing activity on the Website by using cookies and similar technologies. These companies may use such data about you in order to provide recommendations for products and services that might be of interest to you. Some of these companies who provide targeting marketing services to New Balance are located in countries outside of the EEA and where we transfer your information outside of the EEA, we make sure adequate safeguards are used to protect your personal information, including using specific contracts approved by the European Commission and/or ensuring the service providers located in the United States are part of the EU-US Privacy Shield as further described in section [**8\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_8). If you wish to opt-out of this program, you can let us know (see section [**15\. HOW CAN I CONTACT NEW BALANCE IF I HAVE QUESTIONS OR COMPLAINTS ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_15)).

• **Recipients resulting from legal requirements** : We may disclose your personal information:

o if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to protect the rights, property or safety of our business, our customers or others. This includes, in specific cases, sharing information with law enforcement or regulatory agencies, or authorised third parties, in response to a verified request relating to a criminal investigation or actual or suspected violation of law or misuse of our Service that may expose us and/or any customer or third party to legal risks or liability; and 

o to successors in title or replacement operators of all or part of our business.

###  **7\. HOW IS MY PERSONAL INFORMATION KEPT SECURE?**

We have put in place a variety of security measures to protect the personal information we collect about you from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised manner, altered or disclosed.

For example, to ensure the information you provide online is secure during transmission, we use encryption technology and Secure Socket Layers (SSL). These controls are certified by DigiCert®. You can review our security certificate using your browser by clicking on the closed lock or solid key image at the bottom of your browser on any of the secure pages on our site. This will display the Service security information.

As mentioned above, you can choose to store your credit/debit card information in your "My Account" if you wish. To protect your security in these circumstances, we encrypt all stored credit/debit card information and we do not store your card's CVV/CVC number (which, as a precautionary measure, you are required to provide each time you place an order with us). If you choose not to store your credit/debit card information in an account with us, we will only temporarily store your entire encrypted credit/debit card information for as long as is necessary in order to validate your credit card (for example, to automatically contact a credit card company for verification). Once we have done this, we will securely delete your credit/debit card information from our systems.

In addition, we limit access to your personal information to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. They are required to only process your personal information in accordance with our instructions and are subject to a duty of confidentiality. 

### **8\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

The personal information we collect about you is stored on secure servers located within the European Economic Area (“ **EEA** ”) and the United States. In addition, for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy, we may transfer personal information we hold about you outside the EEA to the third parties identified in section [**6\. WITH WHOM DOES NEW BALANCE SHARE MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_6)

The countries concerned may not have similar data protection laws to the EEA. We are required by data protection law to ensure that where we or the third parties listed in this Privacy Policy transfer your personal information outside of the EEA, it is treated securely and is protected against unauthorised access, loss or destruction, unlawful processing and any processing which is inconsistent with the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We do this by ensuring that at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

                      * • In accordance with GDPR Article 46(2), we use specific contracts approved by the European Commission, which give personal information the same protection it has within the EEA. For further details, see [European Commission: Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries.](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en)

                      * • In accordance with GDPR Article 45, where we use service providers based in the United States, we may transfer personal information to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield, which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the EU and US. For further details, see [European Commission: EU-US Privacy Shield.](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/eu-us-privacy-shield_en)

The information in section [**6\. WITH WHOM DOES NEW BALANCE SHARE MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_6) sets out details of which of these safeguards is used to transfer your personal information to each of the third parties based outside of the EEA.

Please ask us if you would like more information about the safeguards that are used to protect your personal information when it is processed outside the EEA (see section [**15\. HOW CAN I CONTACT NEW BALANCE IF I HAVE QUESTIONS OR COMPLAINTS ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_15)).

###  **9\. WHAT IS THE NEW BALANCE CHILDREN'S PRIVACY POLICY?**

We do not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under the age of 13 (a " **Child** "), including from any Child who participates in the Stride I.D. Experience. If you become aware that your Child or a Child for which you have parental responsibility has provided personal information to us without your consent, contact Customer Care toll-free at 0800 802 1057 or email [ customercare@newbalance.co.uk.](https://newbalance.zendesk.com/hc/en-gb/requests/new)

[

If we become aware that a Child has submitted personal information to us, we will promptly delete the information and we will not disclose it to third parties.

](https://newbalance.zendesk.com/hc/en-gb/requests/new)

###  **10\. HOW DO LINKS FROM NEW BALANCE TO OTHER SITES OR APPS AFFECT ME?**

At times, we may provide links from our Website to other websites and applications operated by third parties. These links are provided only for your convenience and intended to add value to your visit. However, we do not have control over these websites and applications, which are independent from New Balance and are subject to separate privacy policies and terms and conditions. When leaving our Website, you need to be aware that this Privacy Policy no longer applies and we are not responsible for your information that third parties may collect through these websites and applications. We strongly encourage you to review the privacy policies and terms and conditions of any third-party websites and applications before using them.

###  **11\. FOR HOW LONG DOES NEW BALANCE KEEP MY PERSONAL INFORMATION FOR?**

We retain your personal information for no longer than is necessary for the purpose(s) for which it was provided in accordance with this Privacy Policy. What this means in practice will vary between different categories of personal information. When determining the relevant retention periods, we take into account factors including:

                        * • legal obligation(s) under applicable law to retain information for a certain period of time;

                        * • statute of limitations under applicable law;

                        * • the warranty period for any products you have purchased from us;

                        * • potential or actual disputes; and

                        * • guidelines issued by relevant data protection authorities.

Otherwise, we securely delete your personal information from our systems when it is no longer needed.

###  **12\. WHAT ARE MY PRIVACY RIGHTS?**

You have the following rights with regard to your personal information:

Rights | What does this mean?  
---|---  
  
1\. Right to be informed 

| 

You have the right to be provided with clear, transparent and easily understandable information about how we use your personal information and your rights. This is why we are providing you with the information in this Privacy Policy.  
  
2\. Right of access

| 

You have the right to obtain access to the personal information that we hold about you and certain other information (similar to that provided in this Privacy Policy).   
  
3\. Right to rectification

| 

You have the right to request that we rectify any personal information that we hold about you if it is inaccurate or incomplete. If you have a “My Account” with us, you can also view and update your contact information, billing and shipping addresses at any time by logging into your “My Account” on our Website. See section [**14\. HOW CAN I ACCESS, UPDATE OR DELETE "MY ACCOUNT" INFORMATION?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_14) for further details.  
  
4\. Right to erasure

| 

This is also known as ‘the right to be forgotten’ and, in simple terms, enables you to request the deletion or removal of the personal information that we hold about you. This is not a general right to erasure; there are exceptions. For example, we have the right to continue using your personal information if such use is necessary for compliance with our legal obligations or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. If you have a “My Account” with us, you can delete your account at any time by logging into your “My Account” on our Website. See section [**14\. HOW CAN I ACCESS, UPDATE OR DELETE "MY ACCOUNT" INFORMATION?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_14) for further details.  
  
5\. Right to restrict processing

| 

You have the right to restrict further use of your personal information where you believe that the information we hold about you is inaccurate, our use of such information is unlawful or if we no longer need to use the information for the purposes for which we hold it. When processing is restricted, we can still store your personal information, but may not use it further.   
  
6\. Right to data portability

| 

You have the right to obtain and reuse the personal information that we hold about you in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, and (where technically feasible) to have such information transmitted to another "data controller", where: (a) this is personal information you provided to us; (b) we are processing such information on the basis of your consent or to perform a contract with you; and (c) the processing is carried out by automated means.  
  
7\. Right to object to processing

| 

You have the right to object to us processing your personal information for our legitimate business purposes or for direct marketing purposes (including in each case any related profiling).  
  
8\. Right to withdraw consent to processing

| 

If you have given your consent to us to process your personal information for a particular purpose (for example, in respect of marketing communications or the Stride I.D. Experience), you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time (although if you do so, it does not mean that any processing of your personal information up to that point is unlawful).   
  
9\. Right to make a complaint to the UK data protection authority

| 

You have the right to make a complaint to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) if you are unhappy with how we have handled your personal information or believe our processing of your personal information does not comply with applicable data protection law.  

For more information about your rights or if you would like to exercise any of your rights, you are welcome to contact us using the contact details set out below under section [**15\. HOW CAN I CONTACT NEW BALANCE IF I HAVE QUESTIONS OR COMPLAINTS ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_15)

Please note that if you ask us to stop using your personal information in a certain way or erase your personal information, and this type of use or personal information is required by us in order to facilitate your use of the Service in any way, you may not be able to use the Service as you did before. This does not include your right to opt out of receiving marketing communications from us, which you can do so at any time without restriction.

###  **13\. HOW CAN I OPT-OUT/UNSUBSCRIBE FROM NEW BALANCE MARKETING EMAILS?**

If for any reason you would like to stop receiving emails sent by New Balance that notify you of upcoming events, promotions, sales, new products or contain other marketing content, simply click the unsubscribe link provided at the bottom of every email or on your My Account page on the Website. This will direct you to an unsubscribe page where you can opt out of receiving our marketing emails. 

### **14\. HOW CAN I ACCESS, UPDATE OR DELETE "MY ACCOUNT" INFORMATION?**

Accounts may be created during the ordering process. You can login to or manage your account by clicking the "My Account" link at the top of any page on our Website.

After logging in, you will be able to modify your identity and contact information, update your billing and shipping addresses and payment card details (if you have chosen to store this information in your account), view past orders, or delete your account completely.

For security purposes, credit/debit card information is not saved with your account unless you specifically request that it be saved by clicking the “save this card” box. In no circumstances will we store your card’s CVV/CVC number.

Remember that you are responsible for protecting the user name and password for your account and, as set forth in the Terms and Conditions, you will be responsible for all activity occurring through the use of your user name and password.

###  **15\. HOW CAN I CONTACT NEW BALANCE IF I HAVE QUESTIONS OR COMPLAINTS ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY?**

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy or would like to exercise any of your privacy rights described above, please contact New Balance at [privacy@newbalance.com.](mailto:privacy@newbalance.com)

If you are not satisfied with our response to any enquiry or complaint or believe our use of your personal information does not comply with applicable data protection law, you can make a complaint to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) by:

                          * • writing to: Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire SK9 5AF;

                          * • calling: 0303 123 1113; or 

                          * • submitting a message through the ICO’s website at:[ www.ico.org.uk.](http://www.ico.org.uk/)

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal information (or to exercise any of your other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive; or we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

We aim to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. However, it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

###  **16\. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND YOUR DUTY TO INFORM US OF CHANGES**

This Privacy Policy was last updated on May 25, 2018.

We recommend that you review this Privacy Policy periodically, as we will update it from time to time. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be posted on the Website and, where appropriate, we will tell you about this through an email notification.

It is important that the personal information we hold about you is accurate and up to date. Please let us know if your personal information changes during your use of the Service.

###  **II. COOKIE POLICY**

This cookie policy (“ **Cookie Policy** ”) applies to information collected through the use of cookies and other similar technologies (collectively referred to in this Cookie Policy as “ **cookies** ”) by New Balance Athletic Shoes (U.K.) Limited (a company registered in England and Wale\s with company number 01616165 and registered address at Appleton House, 430 Birchwood Boulevard, Birchwood, Warrington, Cheshire, WA3 7WD, UK) and its affiliates, (referred to in this Cookie Policy as “ **New Balance** ”, “ **we** ”, “ **us** ” or “ **our** ”) when you access and use:

                          * • www.newbalance.co.uk and any other website operated by or on behalf of New Balance throughout the European Union (together the “ **Website** ”)

This Cookie Policy explains what cookies are, which cookies we use and why, and what you can do to manage your cookie preferences. Where any information we collect through cookies qualifies as personal information, our [**PRIVACY POLICY**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_policy) applies to the collection and use of that information. Please review this Cookie Policy and our [**PRIVACY POLICY**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#privacy_policy) carefully. This Cookie Policy may be updated from time to time. We will post the updated terms on the Website.

This Cookie Policy is provided in a layered format so you can click through to the specific sections set out below:

### [**1\. WHAT ARE COOKIES?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#cookies_1)

### [**2\. WHY DOES NEW BALANCE USE COOKIES?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#cookies_2)

### [**3\. HOW DOES NEW BALANCE USE COOKIES?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#cookies_3)

### [**4\. HOW CAN I MANAGE MY COOKIE PREFERENCES?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#cookies_4)

### [**5\. HOW CAN I CONTACT NEW BALANCE IF I HAVE QUESTIONS OR COMPLAINTS ABOUT THIS COOKIE POLICY?**](https://www.newbalance.co.uk/privacy-policy.html#cookies_5)

### **1\. WHAT ARE COOKIES?**

Cookies are small text files that are transferred and stored by your web browser to your computer or mobile device when you visit or use a website. Cookies contain information that is unique to your web browser, which means they can be used to distinguish you from other website users and allow the website to remember your choices and preferences during your visit.

Cookies can be considered as **‘first party’** or **‘third party’** cookies depending on the domain that places them. **First party cookies** are cookies set by a website visited by the user (so in this instance, are cookies placed by the New Balance on our Website). **Third party cookies** are set by a domain other than that of the website visited by the user, so if a user visits a website and a third party organisation sets a cookie through that website, this would be a third party cookie. New Balance has both first and third party cookies on our Website.

Cookies can also be considered as **‘persistent’** or **‘session’** cookies depending on their duration. Persistent cookies remain on a user's device for the period of time specified in those cookies, and are activated each time that user visits the website that created the cookies, until the cookies expire or are disabled by the user. **Session cookies** allow the actions of a user to be linked during a single browsing session. A session starts when a user opens a browser window and ends when the browser window is closed, following which all session cookies are deleted.

Pixel tags and Web beacons are tiny graphic images that allow us or preferred service providers to track analytic information about your visit to our Website (such as pages viewed or links clicked) and monitor when HTML emails are opened. 

### **2\. WHY DOES NEW BALANCE USE COOKIES?**

We use cookies to collect information about your browsing activity and how you use our services as well as about the device you have used to access our Website (including in some instances the IP address, browser type and mobile device identifiers) so that we can:

                              * • provide essential features and functionality on our Website, such as enabling you to select products, place them in your shopping basket and make a purchase; 
                              * • make our Website as easy and intuitive as possible for you to use;

                              * • monitor and analyse Website usage and performance so that we can measure the effectiveness of our Website, improve how it operates (including security) and the product selection and services available through it;

                              * • recognise you when you return to our Website in order to improve functionality for your benefit, particularly if you have chosen to use the “My Account” service;

                              * • for New Balance to market to you, particularly web banner advertisements and targeted updates;

                              * • alert you to new areas that may be of interest to you; and

                              * • remember certain information about your browsing activity on our Website, such as the web pages or products you have viewed and what your preferences are. This information can then be used to personalise and improve the way you interact with our Website (for example, in terms of displaying content that we think might be relevant to you based on your previous activity) and to inform you of special offers and promotions that are tailored to your interests (where you have consented to receiving marketing communications from us).

We also permit a number of third party cookies on our website to assist and enable our marketing programmes and to meet our contractual obligations to record business transactions that were driven by leads (advertisements/ links) from third party websites.

###  **3\. HOW DOES NEW BALANCE USE COOKIES?**

Different cookies have different functions. Our Website uses the following cookies: 

**Strictly necessary cookies**

These cookies are essential for our Website to operate. For example, they enable you to log into secure areas of our website (such as “My Account”, if you choose to create one) or add products to your shopping basket so you are able to view and pay for these when you have finished browsing. Some of the cookies we use help secure your browsing session and verify that the session is valid. You cannot opt out of these cookies as the Website cannot function properly without them.

**Analytical/performance cookies**

We use some first party cookies and these allow us to measure and analyse how you use our Website so that we can measure the effectiveness of our Website and improve the way our Website works. We also use third party analytics providers to assist us with this process. Our main analytic provider is Google, Inc. through their Google Analytics platform. To find out more about Google Analytics you can follow this link: [https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en-GB.](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en-GB)

You can opt-out of Google analytics. To find out how please visit: [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)

We also use Hotjar Ltd as an analytics provider. To find out more about Hotjar and how to opt-out of their tracking you can visit: [https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out ](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out)

**Functionality cookies**

These cookies allow our Website to remember choices you make when visiting and recognise you when you return in order to provide functionality for your benefit. For example, functionality cookies allow our website to remember settings that are specific to you, such as your login details for “My Account” if you choose to create an account with us, so that you don’t have to log back in from the same device each time you visit (provided the relevant cookie was not disabled in the interim).

**Targeting/advertising cookies**

These cookies track your use of our Website, including the web pages or products you have viewed or put in your shopping basket. This information enables us to build a profile of your preferences so that we can display content on our Website and other websites and apps that is more relevant to you and your interests. This may include delivering targeted advertising on our Website or other websites and apps that you visit, or preventing you being targeted by advertisements or limiting the number of times you see a particular advertisement. We utilise a platform called Lotame to assist us in delivering relevant content and advertising to you. To find out more about Lotame and how you can opt out of the collection and use of your data you can follow this link:[ https://www.lotame.com/about-lotame/privacy/lotames-products-services-privacy-policy/](https://www.lotame.com/about-lotame/privacy/lotames-products-services-privacy-policy/)

In addition, if you have consented to receiving marketing communications from us by email, direct mail, SMS text or telephone, we will use the information collected by these cookies to provide you with special offers and promotions that are tailored to your preferences, based on your previous activity on our Website. These cookies will also enable us to measure and analyse the effectiveness of marketing campaigns. 

Please note that third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies. 

**Tracking cookies**

We work with a number of providers of tracking services. The cookies employed by these service providers allow them to record business transactions generated by third party leads and advertisements and allow us to pay commission to the originators of those leads. The purpose of the tracking cookies is to allocate one successful advertisement to a particular transaction and to perform the corresponding billing services. Personally identifiable information is neither collected nor processed nor used in this tracking. To find out more about these cookies please visit our providers sites:  
• <https://www.conversantmedia.eu/legal/cookie-list>  
• <https://www.awin.com/gb/legal/privacy-policy>

### **4\. HOW CAN I MANAGE MY COOKIE PREFERENCES?**

The analytical/performance, functionality and targeting/advertising cookies on our Website are not strictly necessary for our Website to function but improve the overall performance of our Website and provide you with a better user experience. You can delete or block these cookies by changing the setting on your web browser that allows you to delete or block the setting of some or all cookies. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. Each browser is a little different, so check your browser Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookie settings.

However, please note that if you do delete or block cookies, we cannot ensure that all pages on our Website will be displayed and/or that all the features and functions of our Website will be fully available. However, you can still place orders over the telephone by calling Customer Care toll-free at 0800 802 1057.

Please note that if you use different computers or mobile devices to access and use our Website, you will need to ensure that each web browser on each device is adjusted to suit your cookie preferences.

###  **5\. HOW CAN I CONTACT NEW BALANCE IF I HAVE QUESTIONS OR COMPLAINTS ABOUT THIS COOKIE POLICY?**

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Cookie Policy, please contact Customer `Care toll-free at 0800 802 1057 or email [privacy@newbalance.com.](mailto:privacy@newbalance.com)
